Guide to the New York State Veterinary Medical Society records, 1890-1998.
New York State Veterinary Medical Society records, 1890-1998
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State Veterinary Medical Society records, 1890-1998
2541
New York State Veterinary Medical Society.
3.2 cubic ft.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes, proceedings and correspondence of the Society from 1890 until 1998.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The New York State Veterinary Medical society was founded in Rochester on January 15, 1890, and is still active today.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes, proceedings and correspondence of the Society from its founding in Rochester on January 15, 1890 until 1998. Also included are its constitution and bylaws, code of ethics, various papers presented before it, including one by James Law on poisoning through the milk and meat of tubercular animals (1894), newspaper clippings, lists of qualified or graduated veterinary surgeons in New York State (1890-1900), circulars concerning meetings of the Society, and other entries made by Nelson P. Hinkley, Secretary. Also included is William Henry Kelly's letter impression book (August 1903-March 1905), which he kept as Secretary of the Society, including letters to James Law and Veranus A. Moore and letters concerning the problem of illegal veterinary practice in New York State.
Also, radio scripts from broadcasts by the society, 1931-1936.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State Veterinary Medical Society.; Hinkley, Nelson P.; Kelly, William Henry.; Law, James.; Moore, Veranus A.
Subjects:
Tuberculosis--Transmission.; Veterinarians--Professional ethics--New York (State); Veterinary medicine--New York (State)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Minutes and proceedings, 1890-1894 (Box 1)
- William Henry Kelly's letter impression book, August 1903-March 1905 (Box 1)
- Book of the Law, By-Laws and Constitution, and List of Members, 1890-1906 (Box 5)
- Constitution and Bylaws, 1895, 1907, 1945, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Committee on History-Report, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- History by Lincoln Field, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Accounting and Receipts, 1890-1896 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Accounting and Receipts, 1920-1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Cash accounts, 19-- (Box 7)
- Accounting and Receipts, 1947-1975 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1891-1899 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1900-1901 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Committee on History-General, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Lists of Registered Veterinarians, 1897, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Lists of Registered Veterinarians, 1899 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Lists of Registered Veterinarians, ca. 1890-1900 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Meetings-Programs, 1891-1900 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Meetings-Programs, 1910-1938 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Meetings-Programs, 1939-1970 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Meetings-Programs, 1985-1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Meetings-Minutes, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Meetings-Minutes, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Meetings-Minutes, ca. 1908 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Meetings-Minutes and Reports, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Meetings-Minutes - Annual Mtg, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Meetings-Minutes, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Meetings-Reports, 1956, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Meetings-Reports, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Meetings-Reports, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Meetings-President's Address, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Meetings-President's Address, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Minutes - Proceedings, 1890 (Box 5)
- Minutes - Proceedings, 1894-1895 (Box 5)
- Minutes - Proceedings, 1896-1910 (Box 6)
- Meetings-Proceedings, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Meetings-Proceedings, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Meetings-Misc, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Membership Applications, 1896, 1903-1904 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Membership - Correspondence, ca. 1909-1910 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Newsletter-"Vet College News", ca. 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- N.Y. State Dept. of Ed, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- News Clippings, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- News Clippings, 1950- (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Illegal Practitioners- Krull, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Illegal Practitioners, 1905-1906 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Illegal Practitioners, 1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Illegal Practitioners, 1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Illegal Practitioners, 1909-1910 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Illegal Practitioners, 1909-1910 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Illegal Practitioners, 1909-1910 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Legislation, ca. 1900-1906, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Oswego Milk and Dairy Inspector, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Lease, 1937-1939 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Brink, Arthur - Milk Dealer, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Membership Lists, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous, ca.1920-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Broadcasting Schedule, 1931-1936 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- WGY Radio Talks, Nos. 1-37, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- WGY Radio Talks, Nos. 38-71, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- WGY Radio Talks, Nos. 72-98, 1932-1933 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- WGY Radio Talks, Nos. 100-120, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- WGY Radio Talks, Nos. 121-146, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- WGY Radio Talks, Nos. 147-171, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- WGY Radio Talks, Nos. 172-185, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 8)